ANKITA KHANDEKAR

Software Engineer

+919834896970

ankitakhandekar326@gmail.com ▶

Hyderabad, India 🙆

LinkedIn in

Github 😯

SUMMARY

I am a dedicated and experienced software engineer with 2+ years of professional experience in Java, Spring Boot, and MySQL. My primary focus has been on backend development using the Spring Boot framework. I have actively contributed to the success of my company's projects, playing a crucial role in the backend development.

EDUCATION

Sipna College of Engineering and Technology

BE (ENTC) 2016 -20 CGPA: 9.02/10

Art's, Commerce and Science College

XII 2015-16 Percentage: 86.31 %

Saraswati Vidyalaya

X 2013-14

Percentage: 90.4 %

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages :** Core Java, JavaScript
- Technologies & Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, Microservices (Basic), REST API, HTML, CSS, Angular
- Databases : MySQL, H2 Database
- Development Tools: Eclipse, Spring Tool Suite (STS), MySQL Workbench, VS Code ,Intellij Idea
- Other Tools: JIRA, Postman, Github, Git

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Feb 2023).
- Java Backend Developer Geeks for geeks(Jun 2022).
- Microservices with Java Springboot and Spring Cloud -Udemy (April 2023)
- Vue JS 3 Modern Web Development with Vuex & Vue Router Udemy (Feb 2023)
- Java and SQL Certification- Hacker Rank

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

TEK systems Global Services | 03/2023 - Current

- As part of a backend development team, I played a pivotal role in modernizing and optimizing legacy applications by converting old EJB (Enterprise JavaBeans) code into Spring Boot, ensuring improved performance, scalability, and maintainability.
- Communicating with clients to gather the business requirements, give demos, and receive feedback to make sure there is a positive impact on the business processes.

Associate Engineer

TEKsystems Global Services | 10/2021 - 03/2023

- As a part of the backend development team, I played a vital role in a significant project that involved developing a scalable and secure web application using Spring Boot.
- Tested methodology with writing and execution of test plans, debugging and testing scripts and tools.

Trainee Engineer

TEKsystems Global Services | 07/2021 - 10/2021

- Worked in a dynamic team environment guided by mentors to get hands-on experience and develop business-level applications.
- Built a complete Online Quiz Portal with role-based authentication and authorization.

HONORS & AWARDS

- Received appreciation from a client for spontaneous and exceptional
 effort in the project for displaying dedication, commitment, and ability
 to go above and beyond to deliver value to the customer in Project.
- University Rank 9th Holder in BE (E & TC).
- Merit Scholarship received from multiple organizations like LIC, NMMS, IOCL, and Lila Poonawala Foundation